Merry Christmas!
Happy New Year!
A lot of people believe that this is a season of giving.
If this is the season of giving, let us rededicate ourselves to the act of giving.
Because I know you have not been giving.
You have not been giving.
What is not done well is not done at all.
Let us rededicate ourselves to the act of giving.
This is the season - rededicate yourself.
Let us not forget that Jesus knows our heart and the motive behind our giving.
Sometimes when you want to give, you have a reason of giving.
That is the kind of giving you are giving.
Jesus knows our hearts and the motive behind our giving.
We only have reason of giving - motive behind our love.
You see your brother loves you.
Why does he love you? He has a reason.
Motive behind our care - you care for your brother, you have respect.
- "Emmanuel, sir."
- I look at you and know, "You too, Emmanuel, sir."
He knows our hearts and the motive behind our action.
The reason why many are here today - you have a reason.
Motive behind your giving, love, care.
"Good morning, sir."
"Hello, sir."
The world has turned like that for selfish, classic, material reasons.
If you give to people, to your neighbour
because you're expecting them to give you in return, you give wrongly.
You help your neighbour and you are expecting your neighbour to help you in return -
that is not of God.
God is the Rewarder.
He is the Rewarder.
If you give to your neighbour, brother, sister, whoever you give
because you are expecting them to give you in return,
oh my God - this is the kind of life we are living today.
This is the kind of giving you are doing.
This is the kind of love you express.
This is the kind of care.
You see humility, "Oh, he is humble" - he has a reason.
When you give out what you do not need, that is not sacrifice.
You open your garage, you see fleet of cars, tyres, rice.
You say, "Come on and take anything you like".
The one they are taking, can you ask yourself, "How long ago did you use that one last?"
Tell your neighbour, "When you give out what you do not need, that is not sacrifice".
Giving is sacrifice.
When you give what your life depends on, the next day you wake up
and say, "Oh, this is what I need to use today. I have given it out".
That is sacrifice.
But you have been giving what you do not need, time you do not need.
Tell your neighbour, "Never come around people just because of what you will get
but come around people because of what you can give".
Jesus said in Acts, 20:35, it is more blessed to give than to receive.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Never come around your neighbour just because of what you can get.
You go to the party, you will sit down, they will serve you rice, food, beautiful food
and you will eat. After eating, you take a plastic bag, taking the remaining rice.
You have nothing to give to the celebrant and you are going home -
you are putting a curse on yourself.
This is the life many of us live.
You go to weddings, parties, you sit down.
Instead of you to prepare something with you...
Can you imagine - "Oh, I'm going to this wedding".
You can imagine - "What shall I be expecting?"
"Oh, they are a big family."
"Ok, let me take so and so amount along with me."
"I will not take anything there without giving."
You come around people all the time just because of what you can get
but not what you can give.
That is a shameless future; it is affecting the future.
Jesus said in Acts 20:35, it is more blessed to give than to receive.
If you know that, and they invite you to a party, an occasion,
and you know that occasion is so superior, you may decide not to go
because you know what they will be giving you will be more than what you will give them.
You decide, "No, no, I cannot go there because what I'm going to meet,
what they will serve me, the rice, the provision I will receive there,
I know I will not be able to meet up".
You decide not to go because it is not good for your life.
Tell your neighbour once again, "Never come around people just because of what you will get".
Never come around people just because of what you can get
but come around people because of what you can give.
It is more blessed to give than to receive.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is the life I'm living.
No matter how great you are, if you meet me, the relationship must be mutual.
When you give me two, I give you three.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So to that, you have to be very careful when it comes to relationships
because you want to be a friend of all, everyone.
Are you prepared for that relationship?
Tell your neighbour once again:
Never come around people just because of what you can get
but come around people because of what you can give.
Relationship is mutual.
Jesus said categorically to people in that Book of Acts 20:35,
it is more blessed to give than to receive.
Now today, we are here.
"Jesus, heal me. Jesus, deliver me."
"Jesus, this; Jesus, that."
Whatever you do to the least out there, that you do to God.
How many people have you helped today?
Jesus has no farm; He has no office but people are His office.
How many people have you helped today and you want Jesus to heal you?
How many people have you helped today and you want Jesus to deliver you?
How many people have you helped today and you want Jesus to bless you?
"Give me!"
How many people are you going to help?
Take this.
Never come around people just because of what you can get
but come around people because of what you can give.
Blessed is he who gives than he who receives.
So we are not giving you all this.
This is money but we don't want you to give us.
Go and bless the poor out there.
Look for your neighbour.
People that need you most are out there.
They are your neighbour - not even here.
Your neighbours out there - they need you.
We give you freely; please, go and give them out there.
So, where are we going?
If I help you and you help your neighbour, this world will be at peace.
I help you; you help your neighbour.
I'm your brother's keeper; you are your neighbour's keeper.
Let us be our brother's keeper; the world will be at peace.
Tell your neighbour, "Let us be our brother's keeper; the world will be at peace".
Tell your neighbour again.
Let us be our brother's keeper; the world will be at peace.
Again and again.
Simple.
To be our brother's keeper is when you see your brother frown,
you say, "Brother, what can I do for you? What is wrong?"
You want to know from time to time, "What is going on?"
Be your brother's keeper; don't wait until your brother asks you, "I need your help".
It is not everyone that can ask.
Some people are very... - they are ready to die with their problem.
By countenance, appearance, dominion, you can know that this one is going through some stress.
Your neighbour in the house.
You live in the house, you see children that never go to school.
They play football on Sunday, Monday - every day you see them moving around, playing.
"Where are your parents?"
Invest in the life of people.
This will speak for you tomorrow.
Tell your neighbour, "Invest in the life of people.
This will speak for you in the future".
That is all.
We have not been investing in the life of people; we invest in material.
If you are conscious of the future, you will invest in the lives of people.
Conscious of tomorrow, conscious of next.
Conscious of what will happen tomorrow.
I mean, Merry Christmas, Happy New Year - what will happen this next year?
Begin to invest in the life of people.
Viewers all over the world, Merry Christmas and Happy New Year!
I know you want to go to a party tomorrow - there are a lot of parties.
This is the season of parties - you want to go to a party, wedding, every party.
Oh my brother, prepare.
If they give you three, give them four.
Don't just go there and eat, eat, eat.
Going there and eat, eat, eat - you are eating your career.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You say, "He is a millionaire".
Ok, he is a millionaire. Do you want to eat him?
"He is a millionaire. Let's go there."
I hope you carry a "hula".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 30/12/2018
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 03/01/2019